# Michael F. Zhang

3725 Armour Court, Woodridge, IL 60517 Phone: 630.486.6411 Email: mfzhang2@illinois.edu https://mfzhang2.github.io

## **Objective**

Accumulate and acquire knowledge in the field of Physics.

#### **Professional Statement**

Responsible and motivated young adult with high school diploma in pursuit of a bachelor's degree in Physics. Great with analysis and problem solving as well as communication. Experienced in teaching, explaining, and leading. Well-versed in Mathematics, Physics, and writing.

#### Education

University of Illinois—Urbana-Champaign (2017-present)

Expected Graduation Date (May 2021) | Major: Physics

### **Experience**

Service Desk Analyst Intern at MultiPlan Inc. June 2017 - August 2017	<ul> <li>Handled and processed tickets initiated by healthcare professionals and their respective clients.</li> <li>Completed a project that enabled MultiPlan to comply with mandatory regulations.</li> <li>Presented to the CIO, CTO, and various managers in the Information Technology department.</li> </ul>
First Class Leader at Naperville North High School August 2015 - May 2017	<ul> <li>Led students through interactive activities.</li> <li>Educated peers about issues faced by students such as drug abuse, mental illness, and bullying.</li> <li>Provided support and help for those facing such issues.</li> </ul>
Vice President of Badminton Club during High School August 2016 - May 2017	<ul> <li>Act as stand-in for president when absent.</li> <li>Disseminate information regarding scheduling and promotion.</li> <li>Act as overseer for badminton activities. Set up equipment.</li> </ul>
Humanities Capstone Essay and Presentation Development August 2016 - December 2016	<ul> <li>Involved in an independent study with a supervising mentor in an established school setting.</li> <li>Independently wrote a treatise on philosophical ideas involving humility and introspection.</li> <li>Presented essay to a group of peers.</li> </ul>
Internship at APS at Argonne National Laboratory July 2016 - August 2016	<ul> <li>Developed a Python program currently being used by beamline scientists.</li> <li>Collaborated with the High Pressure Collaborative Access Team to upgrade software.</li> <li>Attended meetings involving scientific discussions.</li> </ul>
Peer Tutor at Naperville North High School August 2015 - May 2016	<ul> <li>Tutored peers one-on-one in various subjects before school in an established school program.</li> <li>Assisted peers in developing critical thinking skills.</li> <li>Overcame challenges as a group in solving problems.</li> </ul>
Science Olympiad Varsity Competitor January 2016 - May 2016	<ul> <li>Self studied topics not included in the standard high school and AP curriculum with my partner.</li> <li>Used computer software to create a simulated protein model and a physical protein model.</li> <li>Competed against various schools in Dupage County in different events.</li> </ul>

#### **Achievements**

Selected as a recipient of the 2017-18 MultiPlan Scholarship award
Selected to receive the 2017 Village of Woodridge/ProLogis Foundation Scholarship Award
National Merit Commended Student
AP Scholar with Distinction
Science Olympiad Varsity Chemistry Lab Event 3rd place medalist

#### Skills

Microsoft Word, Microsoft PowerPoint, Microsoft Excel Java, Python English (fluent), Chinese (Intermediate)